Desmond O'Grady papers, 1953-2001
Emory University
- Writings by Desmond O'Grady, 1956-2002, Series 2; Boxes 28 - 51
  - Poems, 1956-2002, Subseries 2.1; Boxes 28 - 38
    - Collected poems, 1956-2002, Subseries 2.1a; Boxes 28 - 35: folder 6
      - "Father," MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 31, Folder 25)
      - "Female Visitation," TS w/ corrections [variant titles: "Female Guest," "Visitor," "Lady Visitor," and "Xenia"] (Box 31, Folder 26)
      - "Fisherman's Family," TS w/ corrections (Box 31, Folder 27)
      - "Flute Player," TS (Box 31, Folder 28)
      - "FoFo," MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 31, Folder 29)
      - "Funeral," TS w/ corrections (Box 31, Folder 30)
      - "George Barker," TS (Box 31, Folder 31)
      - "Gisele at Eighty," MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 31, Folder 32)
      - "Gisele Triptych," MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 31, Folder 33)
      - "A Glose for Fernando Pessoa," MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 31, Folder 34)
      - "Graveyard," TS w/ corrections [variant title: "The Stony Joke"] (Box 31, Folder 35)
      - "Heir," MS (Box 31, Folder 36)
      - "Her Window," TS w/ corrections (Box 31, Folder 37)
      - "Hermitage," MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 31, Folder 38)
      - "Hiatus," MS and TS w/ corrections [variant titles: "Blank" and "Solstice"] (Box 31, Folder 39)
      - "His Ghost to Hamlet," MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 31, Folder 40)
      - "History," MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 31, Folder 41)
      - "Home Haven," MS and TS w/ corrections [variant titles: "At Sea" and "Dry-Dock"] (Box 31, Folder 42)
      - "Hospitality," MS w/ corrections (Box 31, Folder 43)
      - "House," TS (Box 31, Folder 44)
      - "Impromptu," TS w/ corrections (Box 31, Folder 45)
      - "In Memoriam John Tamburro," MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 31, Folder 46)
      - "In Our Country," MS and TS w/ corrections [variant titles: "In My Country" and "In My Generation"] (Box 32, Folder 1)
      - "The Irish College at Louvain," MS and TS w/ corrections [variant titles: "St. Anthony's Irish College at Louvain" and "Sura"] (Box 32, Folder 2)
      - "An Irish Exile at Liege," MS and TS w/ corrections [variant titles: "Irish Exile," and "Sedulius Scottus: Irish Exile"] (Box 32, Folder 3)
      - "Jack Grootendorst," MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 32, Folder 4)
      - "John Montague at Sixty," MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 32, Folder 5)
      - "Kinsale," MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 32, Folder 6)
      - "Landlord," TS w/ corrections (Box 32, Folder 7)
      - "Logbook," MS and TS w/ corrections [variant titles: "Log," "Walk," and "Winter Walk"] (Box 32, Folder 8)
      - "Midday," MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 32, Folder 9)
      - "Midsummer," TS w/ corrections (Box 32, Folder 10)
      - "Midsummer Day," MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 32, Folder 11)
      - "Midwinter," TS w/ corrections (Box 32, Folder 12)
      - "Morning," TS w/ corrections (Box 32, Folder 13)
      - "My Green Dream," TS w/ corrections (Box 32, Folder 14)
      - "My Rites," MS and TS w/ corrections [variant title: "My Last Rites"] (Box 32, Folder 15)
      - "Nightmare," MS and TS w/ corrections [variant title: "Visitations"] (Box 32, Folder 16)
      - "Nostos," MS w/ corrections (Box 32, Folder 17)
      - "The Old Head of Kinsale," MS and TS w/ corrections [variant title: "The Old Head Said to Me"] (Box 32, Folder 18)
      - "On the Edge," TS w/ corrections (Box 32, Folder 19)
      - "One Easter," MS and TS w/ corrections, [variant title: "Greek Easter"] (Box 32, Folder 20)
      - "A Painter on Her Birthday," TS w/ corrections (Box 32, Folder 21)
      - "Pilgrims," MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 32, Folder 22)
      - "Pub Talk," MS and TS w/ corrections [variant title: "The Chemistry Changes"] (Box 32, Folder 23)
      - "Robert Fitzgerald," MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 32, Folder 24)
      - "Room," MS and TS w/ corrections [variant title: "Picture"] (Box 32, Folder 25)
      - "The Ruin," TS w/ corrections (Box 32, Folder 26)
      - "The Same Anew," MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 32, Folder 27)
      - "Seabird," TS w/ corrections [variant titles: "Spring," "Today," and "Lyric"] (Box 32, Folder 28)
      - "Self-Portrait," MS w/ corrections (Box 32, Folder 29)
      - "Shannon River," TS w/ corrections (Box 32, Folder 30)
      - "A Son's Birthday," MS and TS w/ corrections [variant title: "My Son's Birthday"] (Box 32, Folder 31)
      - "The Spaniard Inn, Kinsale," MS and TS w/ corrections [variant title: "My Day at the Spaniard"] (Box 32, Folder 32)
      - "Spring," TS w/ corrections (Box 32, Folder 33)
      - "Spring Near Salzburg," MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 32, Folder 34)
      - "Squall," MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 32, Folder 35)
      - "Stella Maris," MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 32, Folder 36)
      - "Summer Days," TS w/ corrections [variant title: "Days"] (Box 32, Folder 37)
      - "Sunrise," TS w/ corrections (Box 32, Folder 38)
      - "Tell Me No More," MS and TS w/ corrections [variant title: "Love, Tell Me No More"] (Box 32, Folder 39)
      - "Three Photographs," MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 32, Folder 40)
      - "Timothy O'Keeffe," MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 32, Folder 41)
      - "Tipperary," MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 32, Folder 42)
      - "Village Carpenter," TS w/ corrections (Box 32, Folder 43)
      - "Village Holiday," TS w/ corrections (Box 33, Folder 1)
      - "Viola," MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 33, Folder 2)
      - "Weekend," MS and TS w/ corrections [variant title: "Solo"] (Box 33, Folder 3)
      - "Wild Dogs," TS (Box 33, Folder 4)
      - "A Willow Sprig," MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 33, Folder 5)
      - "Winter," TS w/ corrections (Box 33, Folder 6)
      - "Winter Near Salzburg," MS and TS w/ corrections [variant titles: "Winter at Salzburg" and "Winter in Salzburg"] (Box 33, Folder 7)
      - "With Johannes Edfelt in Sweden, 1986," TS w/ corrections (Box 33, Folder 8)
      - "Woman," TS (Box 33, Folder 9)
      - "Work Break," TS w/ corrections (Box 33, Folder 10)
      - "Works and Days," TS w/ corrections (Box 33, Folder 11)
      - Book jacket material, TS w/ corrections (Box 33, Folder 12)
      - Preliminary table of contents, MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 33, Folder 13)
      - Tipperary, proof w/ corrections (Box 33, Folder 14)
      - My Fields This Springtime (1993)
      - My Fields This Springtime, MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 33, Folder 15)
      - My Fields This Springtime, Proofs w/ corrections (Box 33, Folder 16)
      - The Road Taken: Poems 1956-1996 (1997)
      - Alexandrian Notebook, edited for The Road Taken: Poems 1956-1996, printed (Box 33, Folder 17)
      - Chords and Orchestrations, edited for The Road Taken: Poems 1956-1996, printed (Box 33, Folder 18)
      - The Dark Edge of Europe, edited for The Road Taken: Poems 1956-1996, printed (Box 33, Folder 19)
      - The Dying Gaul, edited for The Road Taken: Poems 1956-1996, printed (Box 34, Folder 1)
      - Hellas, edited for The Road Taken: Poems 1956-1996, TS and printed (Box 34, Folder 2)
      - His Skaldcrane's Nest, edited for The Road Taken: Poems 1956-1996, printed (Box 34, Folder 3)
      - My Fields This Springtime, edited for The Road Taken: Poems 1956-1996, printed (Box 34, Folder 4)
      - Reilly, edited for The Road Taken: Poems 1956-1996, printed (Box 34, Folder 5)
      - Separations, edited for The Road Taken: Poems 1956-1996, printed (Box 34, Folder 6)
      - Sing Me Creation, edited for The Road Taken: Poems 1956-1996, printed (Box 34, Folder 7)
      - Tipperary, editied for The Road Taken: Poems 1956-1996, printed (Box 34, Folder 8)
      - The Wandering Celt, edited for The Road Taken: Poems 1956-1996, TS (Box 34, Folder 9)
      - The Road Taken: Poems 1956-1996, proof w/ corrections [Folder 1 of 4] (Box 34, Folder 10)
      - The Road Taken: Poems 1956-1996, proof w/ corrections [Folder 2 of 4] (Box 35, Folder 1)
      - The Road Taken: Poems 1956-1996, proof w/ corrections [Folder 3 of 4] (Box 35, Folder 2)
      - The Road Taken: Poems 1956-1996, proof w/ corrections [Folder 4 of 4] (Box 35, Folder 3)
      - Book jacket material, MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 35, Folder 4)
      - Preliminary table of contents, MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 35, Folder 5)
      - The Battle of Kinsale 1601 (2002)
      - The Battle of Kinsale 1601, MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 35, Folder 6)
    - Uncollected poems, Subseries 2.1b; Boxes 35: folder 7 - 38
      - "About Beauty," TS w/ corrections (Box 35, Folder 7)
      - "Aftermath," TS w/ corrections (Box 35, Folder 8)
      - "Alexandrian Elegy," MS w/ corrections [variant title: "Dear Alexandria"] (Box 35, Folder 9)
      - "Annunciation," MS w/ corrections (Box 35, Folder 10)
      - "Arrival Egypt," TS (Box 35, Folder 11)
      - "Ashore," MS w/ corrections (Box 35, Folder 12)
      - "Askew," MS w/ corrections (Box 35, Folder 13)
      - "At a Glance," MS w/ corrections [variant title: "One Glance"] (Box 35, Folder 14)
      - "At the Cafe Door," TS (Box 35, Folder 15)
      - "Autumn Festival," MS w/ corrections (Box 35, Folder 16)
      - "Balcony," MS w/ corrections (Box 35, Folder 17)
      - "Ballady Man," MS (Box 35, Folder 18)
      - "Birthday Card," TS w/ corrections [variant title: "August 27"] (Box 35, Folder 19)
      - "Birthday Card for Wolfgang Frommel at 80," MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 36, Folder 1)
      - "Boston's Jake," TS w/ corrections (Box 36, Folder 2)
      - "By the Shannon Waters," MS w/ corrections (Box 36, Folder 3)
      - "Cathy's Sixteenth Birthday Song," MS w/ corrections (Box 36, Folder 4)
      - "Central European Sura," TS w/ corrections (Box 36, Folder 5)
      - "Chadura Taverna," MS w/ corrections (Box 36, Folder 6)
      - "The City," TS (Box 36, Folder 7)
      - "City Encounter," TS w/ corrections (Box 36, Folder 8)
      - "Conversation," MS (Box 36, Folder 9)
      - "Crosstalk," MS w/ corrections (Box 36, Folder 10)
      - "Crow and Poet," MS w/ corrections (Box 36, Folder 11)
      - "Danae and Perseus," MS w/ corrections (Box 36, Folder 12)
      - "A Day in Austria," MS w/ corrections (Box 36, Folder 13)
      - "Days of 1903," TS (Box 36, Folder 14)
      - "The Desert," MS w/ corrections (Box 36, Folder 15)
      - "Dessie Old Kid," MS and TS w/ corrections [variant title: "Billy the Kid"] (Box 36, Folder 16)
      - "Dicey Reilly," MS w/ corrections (Box 36, Folder 17)
      - "Dream," MS w/ corrections (Box 36, Folder 18)
      - "Edge," TS w/ corrections [variant titles: "City" and "New York"] (Box 36, Folder 19)
      - "Egyptian Arrival," TS w/ corrections (Box 36, Folder 20)
      - "Empty," MS w/ corrections (Box 36, Folder 21)
      - "Evening," TS (Box 36, Folder 22)
      - "Far Away," TS (Box 36, Folder 23)
      - "Farewell to Alexandria," MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 36, Folder 24)
      - "Festival," MS w/ corrections (Box 36, Folder 25)
      - "The First Sonnet," MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 36, Folder 26)
      - "Footsteps," TS (Box 36, Folder 27)
      - "For My Father on His Reaching Middle-Age," MS (Box 36, Folder 28)
      - "Franklin Street," TS w/ corrections [variant title: "Street"] (Box 36, Folder 29)
      - "Fred Thompson," MS w/ corrections (Box 36, Folder 30)
      - "Friday Thirteenth," MS w/ corrections (Box 36, Folder 31)
      - "From the Roofs," TS w/ corrections (Box 36, Folder 32)
      - "Funerals of Friends," MS w/ corrections [variant titles: "Friends at Funerals" and "Logbook"] (Box 36, Folder 33)
      - "Grandson," MS w/ corrections (Box 36, Folder 34)
      - "The Great Refinement," MS w/ corrections (Box 36, Folder 35)
      - "Grey," TS (Box 36, Folder 36)
      - "Halloween," MS w/ corrections [variant title: "Goodnight"] (Box 36, Folder 37)
      - "He Came to Read," TS (Box 36, Folder 38)
      - "He Swears," TS (Box 36, Folder 39)
      - "The Headgear of the Tribe," MS w/ corrections (Box 36, Folder 40)
      - "Her Audience," TS w/ corrections (Box 36, Folder 41)
      - "Her Birthday Night," MS w/ corrections (Box 36, Folder 42)
      - "Hericleia," MS w/ corrections (Box 36, Folder 43)
      - "Hermit and Harlot," MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 36, Folder 44)
      - "Illi Shuftu: The Things I Have Seen," MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 36, Folder 45)
      - "In Defence of Old Age," MS w/ corrections (Box 36, Folder 46)
      - "In Memoriam Michael Hartnett," MS and TS w/ corrections [variant titles: "Elegy for Michael Hartnett," and "Two Sides of Life's Coin"] (Box 36, Folder 47)
      - "Island Neighbour," MS (Box 36, Folder 48)
      - "La Tene Sura," TS (Box 36, Folder 49)
      - "The Last Sonnet," MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 36, Folder 50)
      - "Letter to Derek Mahon from Midstream," MS (Box 36, Folder 51)
      - "Like Father, Like Son," MS w/ corrections (Box 37, Folder 1)
      - "Love," MS w/ corrections (Box 37, Folder 2)
      - "Love Dance," MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 37, Folder 3)
      - "Love Elegy," MS w/ corrections [variant title: "True Love"] (Box 37, Folder 4)
      - "Makers and Breakers," MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 37, Folder 5)
      - "May Day," MS w/ corrections (Box 37, Folder 6)
      - "Meander," MS w/ corrections (Box 37, Folder 7)
      - "Memory," TS w/ corrections (Box 37, Folder 8)
      - "Midnight," TS and MS w/ corrections (Box 37, Folder 9)
      - "Mill Stream Tree," MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 37, Folder 10)
      - "Mise Eire," TS w/ corrections (Box 37, Folder 11)
      - "Monday Morning," MS w/ corrections (Box 37, Folder 12)
      - "The Month of Athyr," TS (Box 37, Folder 13)
      - "Morning," TS w/ corrections (Box 37, Folder 14)
      - "My Gift," MS w/ corrections (Box 37, Folder 15)
      - "My Muse," MS (Box 37, Folder 16)
      - "Mycenae," TS (Box 37, Folder 17)
      - "Nausicaa," TS w/ corrections [variant titles: "Girl" and "Sabina"] (Box 37, Folder 18)
      - "Nero's Reign," TS w/ corrections (Box 37, Folder 19)
      - "New Life," MS w/ corrections [variant title: "Kyrie Eleision"] (Box 37, Folder 20)
      - "1944," TS (Box 37, Folder 21)
      - "North Country Fare," MS w/ corrections (Box 37, Folder 22)
      - "Off," TS (Box 37, Folder 23)
      - "Old Haunts," MS w/ corrections (Box 37, Folder 24)
      - "On the Train," TS w/ corrections (Box 37, Folder 25)
      - "One Night," TS (Box 37, Folder 26)
      - "One of Them," TS w/ corrections (Box 37, Folder 27)
      - "One Week," TS w/ corrections (Box 37, Folder 28)
      - "Oral Tradition," MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 37, Folder 29)
      - "Overview," MS w/ corrections (Box 37, Folder 30)
      - "Painting the Fields of Paradise," MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 37, Folder 31)
      - "Pajamas," MS w/ corrections (Box 37, Folder 32)
      - "Parma," MS w/ corrections [variant title: "The City"] (Box 37, Folder 33)
      - "Passed," TS (Box 37, Folder 34)
      - "Passer By," MS and TS w/ corrections [variant titles: "Move On," "Pass Bye," and "View"] (Box 37, Folder 35)
      - "Pescolani," MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 37, Folder 36)
      - "Points of View," MS w/ corrections (Box 37, Folder 37)
      - "Presence," TS w/ corrections (Box 37, Folder 38)
      - "Profiles," MS w/ corrections (Box 37, Folder 39)
      - "Rearing Balthazar," MS w/ corrections (Box 37, Folder 40)
      - "Relations," MS w/ corrections [variant title: "Visitors"] (Box 37, Folder 41)
      - "Requiem for Paddy O'Reilly," TS w/ corrections (Box 37, Folder 42)
      - "Return," MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 37, Folder 43)
      - "Returning to Cairo," MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 37, Folder 44)
      - "Romanesque Sura," TS w/ corrections (Box 37, Folder 45)
      - "Routine," TS (Box 38, Folder 1)
      - "The Scar," MS and TS w/ corrections [See also Subseries 2.1, Poetry, Alexandrian Notebook, Preliminary table of contents, MS] (Box 38, Folder 2)
      - "Scribble," MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 38, Folder 3)
      - "Seachange," MS (Box 38, Folder 4)
      - "Seasons," MS w/ corrections [variant titles: "Our Seasons" and "This Time of Year"] (Box 38, Folder 5)
      - "She's My Camel," MS w/ corrections (Box 38, Folder 6)
      - "Since Ever Already," TS (Box 38, Folder 7)
      - "Siren," MS w/ corrections (Box 38, Folder 8)
      - "Snapshot," MS w/ corrections (Box 38, Folder 9)
      - "So," MS w/ corrections (Box 38, Folder 10)
      - "Soft Rain Came Last Night, Now All's Green in Sight," MS w/ corrections (Box 38, Folder 11)
      - "Son," MS w/ corrections (Box 38, Folder 12)
      - "The Squeak in My Heart," MS w/ corrections (Box 38, Folder 13)
      - "Stay," TS (Box 38, Folder 14)
      - "Stockholm, 1986," MS w/ corrections (Box 38, Folder 15)
      - "Suburban Recluse," MS (Box 38, Folder 16)
      - "Sumup," MS w/ corrections (Box 38, Folder 17)
      - "Termopylae," TS (Box 38, Folder 18)
      - "That House," TS (Box 38, Folder 19)
      - "These Moments," MS w/ corrections (Box 38, Folder 20)
      - "Thinking," TS w/ corrections (Box 38, Folder 21)
      - "This Island," MS w/ corrections [variant titles: "Bohemia Borders the Sea" and "The Island Borders Europe"] (Box 38, Folder 22)
      - "Those Who Fought for the Achaen League," TS (Box 38, Folder 23)
      - "Time Passes," MS w/ corrections (Box 38, Folder 24)
      - "To Marcella Altieri on Her Birthday 1991," MS w/ corrections (Box 38, Folder 25)
      - "To My Daughter Gisele from Rome," MS w/ corrections (Box 38, Folder 26)
      - "Tobacco Kiosk," TS (Box 38, Folder 27)
      - "The Tomb of Iases," TS (Box 38, Folder 28)
      - "A Town of Osroene," TS (Box 38, Folder 29)
      - "Tuscan Sura," MS w/ corrections (Box 38, Folder 30)
      - "The Twenty Fifth Sonnet," MS w/ corrections (Box 38, Folder 31)
      - "Unfinished Pieta," MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 38, Folder 32)
      - "View," MS w/ corrections (Box 38, Folder 33)
      - "Vocation," MS w/ corrections (Box 38, Folder 34)
      - "Voices," TS (Box 38, Folder 35)
      - "Waiting for the Barbarians," MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 38, Folder 36)
      - "Wedding Anniversary," MS and TS (Box 38, Folder 37)
      - "Whales," MS w/ corrections [variant title: "Poet as Whale"] (Box 38, Folder 38)
      - "The Wild Rover," MS [See Subseries 2.1 Poetry, Uncollected, "Dicey Reilly"] (Box -, -)
      - "A Winter's Night," MS w/ corrections (Box 38, Folder 39)
      - "The Woman at the Well," MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 38, Folder 40)
      - "Work," MS (Box 38, Folder 41)
      - "You," MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 38, Folder 42)
      - Unidentified poetry, MS and TS (Box 38, Folder 43)
      - Unidentified poetry, MS and TS (Box 38, Folder 44)
  - Prose, Subseries 2.2; Boxes 39 - 40
    - Essays, Articles, and Reviews
    - "Anna Akhmatova," TS w/ corrections (Box 39, Folder 1)
    - "Autumn 1991-June 1992," MS w/ corrections (Box 39, Folder 2)
    - "Beckett in Paris," MS and proof w/ corrections (Box 39, Folder 3)
    - "Beckett Reminescences," MS (Box 39, Folder 4)
    - "The Birth of a Book," MS w/ corrections (Box 39, Folder 5)
    - Brief Autobiography, MS (Box 39, Folder 6)
    - "Cairo Trip 10-24 October, 1989, MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 39, Folder 7)
    - "Cavafy: An Exile from Exile," MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 39, Folder 8)
    - "Cavafy and Cubism," MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 39, Folder 9)
    - "Cavafy and Joyce," MS w/ corrections (Box 39, Folder 10)
    - "Childhood Holidays," MS w/ corrections (Box 39, Folder 11)
    - "The Colloquy with the Ancients," TS w/ corrections (Box 39, Folder 12)
    - "Constantine Cavafy," MS w/ corrections (Box 39, Folder 13)
    - " The Dark Edge of Europe, Tim O'Keeffe," MS w/ corrections (Box 39, Folder 14)
    - "Discoveries as a Source of Poetic Inspiration," MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 39, Folder 15)
    - "Early American Poetry," MS w/ corrections (Box 39, Folder 16)
    - "18th Century Anglo-Irish Poetry," MS w/ corrections (Box 39, Folder 17)
    - "Ezra Pound and Creative Translation," MS w/ corrections (Box 39, Folder 18)
    - "The First Prague International Writers' Meeting," MS w/ corrections (Box 39, Folder 19)
    - "Five Poets and Their Poems," MS w/ corrections [review of Sebastian Barry's The Water Colourist, Seamus Deane's History Lessons, Paul Durcan's Jumping the Train Tracks with Angela, Seamus Heaney's An Open Letter, and Julie O'Callaghan's Edible Anecdotes] (Box 39, Folder 20)
    - "Gisele: Painter in Paros 1965-1982," MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 39, Folder 21)
    - "Greece, Naoussa: Summer 1966, MS w/ corrections (Box 39, Folder 22)
    - "The Greek Image," MS w/ corrections (Box 39, Folder 23)
    - "Herzl Emanuel," MS w/ corrections (Box 39, Folder 24)
    - "In Memoriam: Timothy O'Keeffe," MS w/ corrections (Box 39, Folder 25)
    - Introduction to Johnet Dillon's Paper Poems, MS w/ corrections (Box 39, Folder 26)
    - "Jack Donovan," MS w/ corrections (Box 39, Folder 27)
    - "Jack Murphy," TS w/ corrections (Box 39, Folder 28)
    - "The James Dorothy Flanagan Memorial English Prize at St. Mary's College, Dundelk, 4 June 1990," MS w/ corrections (Box 39, Folder 29)
    - "Joseph Brodsky," MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 39, Folder 30)
    - "Leaving Limerick," MS w/ corrections (Box 39, Folder 31)
    - "Man's Quest," MS w/ corrections (Box 39, Folder 32)
    - "Modern Arabic Poetry," TS w/ corrections (Box 39, Folder 33)
    - "Modern Greek Poetry," MS w/ corrections (Box 39, Folder 34)
    - "The Modern Novel," MS w/ corrections (Box 39, Folder 35)
    - "A Night With Osers," MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 39, Folder 36)
    - "A Note on Anthony Raftery," TS w/ corrections (Box 39, Folder 37)
    - "Opening Address to the Eleventh Congress of the World Organization of Poets," MS w/ corrections (Box 39, Folder 38)
    - "The Overseas School of Rome, 1965, MS w/ corrections (Box 39, Folder 39)
    - "Pablo Neruda at Spolito," MS w/ corrections (Box 39, Folder 40)
    - "Patrick Kavanagh in Rome, 1965: A Personal Memoir," MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 39, Folder 41)
    - "Patrick Shelley," MS w/ corrections (Box 40, Folder 1)
    - "Peter Russell: A Protean Poet," MS and proof w/ corrections (Box 40, Folder 2)
    - "The Physical Presence of the Muse: A Memoir of Olga Rudge (1895-1996), MS and proof w/ corrections (Box 40, Folder 3)
    - "Player and Poet," MS w/ corrections (Box 40, Folder 4)
    - "Poetry a Marvel of Spirituality/Love," MS w/ corrections (Box 40, Folder 5)
    - "The Poetry of Ennis DeSantis," MS w/ corrections (Box 40, Folder 6)
    - "Portugal Papers," MS w/ corrections (Box 40, Folder 7)
    - "The Presence of Ancient Greece in Mondern English Poetry," TS w/ corrections (Box 40, Folder 8)
    - "The Presence of the Past in the Creative," MS w/ corrections (Box 40, Folder 9)
    - "Procida 1965," MS w/ corrections (Box 40, Folder 10)
    - "Raoul Peter Jackson," MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 40, Folder 11)
    - "Reading the Gododdin," TS w/ corrections (Box 40, Folder 12)
    - Review of Doreen Anwen's Nile Reflections, MS w/ corrections (Box 40, Folder 13)
    - Review of Doreen Anwen's We Live and Remember, MS and TS (Box 40, Folder 14)
    - Review of Neil Chiodo's "Loud in War," MS w/ corrections (Box 40, Folder 15)
    - "Richard Ellmann and Some Paris Irish of the Fifties," TS w/ corrections (Box 40, Folder 16)
    - "The Role of Poetry in Ireland," TS (Box 40, Folder 17)
    - "Rome, Spring 1965," MS w/ corrections (Box 40, Folder 18)
    - "Rome Visit, September 18, 1990-18 April, 1991," MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 40, Folder 19)
    - "The Sculpture of Herzl Emanuel," MS w/ corrections (Box 40, Folder 20)
    - "Sebastian Barry: Writer, Poet," MS w/ corrections (Box 40, Folder 21)
    - "Sligo-Ireland," MS w/ corrections (Box 40, Folder 22)
    - "SOCRATES: The Public Libraries Project," MS w/ corrections (Box 40, Folder 23)
    - Speech given to the American University in Cairo, MS w/ corrections (Box 40, Folder 24)